<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Container version="2">
  <Name>A1111-WebUI-Aegisnir</Name>
  <Repository>a1111-webui-aegisnir:latest</Repository>
  <Registry></Registry>
  <Icon>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aegisnir/A1111-unraid/main/icon.svg</Icon>
  <ExtraParams>--runtime=nvidia</ExtraParams>
  <PostArgs></PostArgs>
  <Description>
    AUTOMATIC1111 Stable Diffusion WebUI for Unraid.

    This template is configured for a locally built image named a1111-webui-aegisnir:latest.
    Build the image on your Unraid host before creating the container from this template.

    DATA DIRECTORY WARNING:
    The path used with --data-dir grows very large very quickly because it can hold models, outputs, extensions, caches, and other working data.
    I recommend storing it outside of appdata when possible.
    You can still place it inside appdata if you want the convenience, but it may consume space very quickly and can fill the location you use for Docker-related storage.

    The default host path is set to /mnt/user/ai/data/ so the large working set lives outside appdata by default.
  </Description>
  <Overview>
  This template expects a locally built Docker image named a1111-webui-aegisnir:latest.
  It does not pull from Docker Hub unless you change the Repository field to a published image.
  The default Extra Parameters include --runtime=nvidia so Docker can expose the NVIDIA runtime inside the container.

    This template passes Automatic1111 data storage through --data-dir.

    - Models, outputs, extensions, caches, and other working data are stored in the mapped data share instead of the container filesystem.
    - This allows you to preserve your models and outputs across container updates and manage them from the host more easily.
    - The data directory can grow very large very quickly, so I recommend storing it outside of appdata when possible.
    - Appdata works if you prefer it, but be aware of how quickly it can fill your Docker storage area.
    - If startup fails with a Torch GPU check error, you can temporarily add --skip-torch-cuda-test to COMMANDLINE_ARGS for troubleshooting.
    - I do not recommend using --skip-torch-cuda-test as a permanent default because it can mask real GPU passthrough issues.
  </Overview>
  <Category>AI:</Category>
  <WebUI>http://[IP]:[PORT:7860]</WebUI>
  <Network>bridge</Network>
  <Privileged>false</Privileged>
  <Project>https://github.com/AUTOMATIC1111/stable-diffusion-webui</Project>
  <Support>https://github.com/aegisnir/A1111-unraid</Support>
  <Changelog>https://github.com/aegisnir/A1111-unraid/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</Changelog>
  <TemplateURL>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aegisnir/A1111-unraid/main/template.xml</TemplateURL>

  <!--
    Changelog: Linked to the repo's CHANGELOG.md for update tracking.
    Support: Points to the repo issues page for help.
    TemplateURL: Always points to the latest template in main.
  -->
    <Config Name="WebUI" Type="Port" Target="7860" Default="7860" Mode="tcp" Display="always" Required="true" Mask="false" Description="Port exposed by the AUTOMATIC1111 WebUI (default: 7860)."/>
    <Config Name="Data Directory" Type="Path" Target="/data" Default="/mnt/user/ai/data/" Mode="rw" Display="always" Required="true" Mask="false" Description="Host path mapped to --data-dir. Default: /mnt/user/ai/data/ (outside appdata)."/>
    <Config Name="Extra Args" Type="Variable" Target="COMMANDLINE_ARGS" Default="--listen --port 7860 --data-dir /data" Display="advanced" Required="false" Mask="false" Description="Extra arguments for launch.py. Default includes --data-dir /data. For GPU errors, try adding --skip-torch-cuda-test."/>
</Container>